<?xml version="1.0"?>
<programs>
<!DOCTYPE programs SYSTEM "sb-db.dtd">
  <program name="ant" version="1.7.1" revision="5"
  systype="*-aix*|*-hpux11.[123]*|*-linux*|*-solaris*">
    <build-name>apache-${SB_PROG_NAME}-${SB_PROG_VER}</build-name>

    <install-name>${SB_PROG_NAME}17</install-name>

    <sources>
      <source checksum="0d68db4a1ada5c91bcbf53cefd0c2fd7"
        checksum-type="md5" size="6979386"
        path="src/apache-ant-1.7.1-src.tar.bz2"/>
      <patch checksum="781b9be491cd46c9a34e3cbd22bdf2bc"
        checksum-type="md5" size="11474"
        path="src/apache-ant-1.7.1.tww.patch"/>
      <patch checksum="3353e1ccf9d5a053bedd85817caee59d"
        checksum-type="md5" size="441"
        path="src/apache-ant-1.7.1.remove-jai.patch"/>
      <patch checksum="fd1484d5a42246629c9b025d5e35d8a5"
        checksum-type="md5" size="464"
        path="src/apache-ant-1.7.1.remove-netrexx.patch"/>
      <patch checksum="affb6bcf20378dabfeb6fba65b25fabc"
        checksum-type="md5" size="455"
        path="src/apache-ant-1.7.1.remove-starteam.patch"/>
      <patch checksum="9f9d7292b86c246184ac4cc3b592da45"
        checksum-type="md5" size="476"
        path="src/apache-ant-1.7.1.remove-stylebook.patch"/>
      <patch checksum="00b2afae69980d05c40ef6d9974bf9b7"
        checksum-type="md5" size="738"
        path="src/apache-ant-1.7.1.remove-weblogic.patch"/>
      <source checksum="01cc9a2a454dd33dcd8c856ec89af090"
        checksum-type="md5" size="1816180"
        path="src/antlr-2.7.7.tar.gz"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <patch checksum="52a22616837ccdb349d21ad1f136c933"
        checksum-type="md5" size="1731"
        path="src/antlr-2.7.7.tww.patch"
        destdir="antlr-2.7.7"/>
      <patch checksum="c5a45c763edd59074b9cae7dd568382e"
        checksum-type="md5" size="26523"
        path="src/antlr-2.7.7.auto.patch"
        destdir="antlr-2.7.7"/>
      <source checksum="6cca1b1b84ff6eb6340ddeb4d73b9335"
        checksum-type="md5" size="584571"
        path="src/bcel-5.2-src.zip"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="699b883d5d83f473d56bc5a66f7f9264"
        checksum-type="md5" size="4120118"
        path="src/bcel-5.2.zip"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="6c22e6733f4ba9d755a437375e3d476e"
        checksum-type="md5" size="643042"
        path="src/junit4.3.1.zip"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="5e360abc01931d237612bd6a02870216"
        checksum-type="md5" size="232413"
        path="src/bsf-bin-2.4.0.tar.gz"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="e5de09672af9b386c30a311654d8541a"
        checksum-type="md5" size="817240"
        path="src/commons-logging-1.1.1-bin.tar.gz"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="577e90cc40328c287acc921dae344c12"
        checksum-type="md5" size="614579"
        path="src/commons-net-1.4.1.tar.gz"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="6f7690c6ba9750e3cbb8ebd10078a79a"
        checksum-type="md5" size="345304"
        path="src/jakarta-oro-2.0.8.tar.gz"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="e55a9e5a44eb55fa588d1020544226f1"
        checksum-type="md5" size="379593"
        path="src/jaf-1_1_1.zip"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="21296bdf2e55f2449ab4471b02503a5b"
        checksum-type="md5" size="2489151"
        path="src/javamail-1_4_1.zip"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="4e979c0dda766ba1dd719905ca975c7b"
        checksum-type="md5" size="302836"
        path="src/jdepend-2.9.zip"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="d8f957ca3da037cb37e76d13e0e18bd6"
        checksum-type="md5" size="35303"
        path="src/jzlib.jar"
        noop="1" var="JZLIB"/>
      <source checksum="16343735dd7d26fa2d403d2dd4852fb0"
        checksum-type="md5" size="210429"
        path="src/jsch.jar"
        noop="1" var="JSCH"/>
      <source checksum="10f04abe4d68d5a89e8eb167e4e45e1a"
        checksum-type="md5" size="2099264"
        path="src/apache-log4j-1.2.15.tar.gz"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="b941b8f4de297827f3211c2cb34af199"
        checksum-type="md5" size="170142"
        path="src/jakarta-regexp-1.5.tar.gz"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
      <source checksum="46d52acdb67ba60f0156043f30108766"
        checksum-type="md5" size="262701"
        path="src/xml-commons-resolver-1.2.tar.gz"
        destdir="apache-ant-1.7.1"/>
    </sources>

    <dependencies>
      <depend program="python" var="PYTHON" install-name="python27"
        type="build">v&gt;=2.7.2</depend>
      <depend program="perl" var="PERL"
        type="build">v==5.12.2</depend>
    </dependencies>

    <script-header>
<![CDATA[
_docdir="${SB_INSTALL_PREFIX}/doc"
_docsubdir="doc"
_sysconfdir="${SB_INSTALL_PREFIX}/etc"
_sysconfsubdir="etc"

case "${SB_SYSTYPE}" in
*-aix*)
  export JAVA_HOME=/usr/java5 ;;
*-hpux*)
  export JAVA_HOME=/opt/java1.5 ;;
*-linux*)
  export JAVA_HOME=/opt/java1.5 ;;
*-solaris*)
  export JAVA_HOME=/opt/java1.5 ;;
esac

export ANT_HOME=${SB_INSTALL_PREFIX}
PATH="${JAVA_HOME}/bin:${PATH}"
]]>
    </script-header>

    <configure>
<![CDATA[
${SB_PATH_SED} -i -e "\
s!{dist.dir}/docs!{dist.dir}/${_docsubdir}!; \
s!{dist.dir}/etc!{dist.dir}/${_sysconfsubdir}!;" build.xml

${SB_PATH_SED} -i -e "\
s!@prefix@!${SB_INSTALL_PREFIX}!;" src/script/ant
]]>
    </configure>

    <build>
<![CDATA[
CLASSPATH="${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/jakarta-regexp-1.5/jakarta-regexp-1.5.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/antlr-2.7.7/antlr.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/bcel-5.2/bcel-5.2.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/jaf-1.1.1/activation.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/javamail-1.4.1/mail.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/jdepend-2.9/lib/jdepend-2.9.jar:\
${SB_SRC_JZLIB}:${SB_SRC_JSCH}:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/junit4.3.1/junit-4.3.1.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/commons-logging-1.1.1/commons-logging-1.1.1.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/commons-net-1.4.1/commons-net-1.4.1.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/apache-log4j-1.2.15/log4j-1.2.15.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/jakarta-oro-2.0.8/jakarta-oro-2.0.8.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/bsf-2.4.0/lib/bsf.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/xml-commons-resolver-1.2/resolver.jar" \
./bootstrap.sh
]]>
    </build>

    <install>
<![CDATA[
CLASSPATH="${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/jakarta-regexp-1.5/jakarta-regexp-1.5.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/antlr-2.7.7/antlr.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/bcel-5.2/bcel-5.2.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/jaf-1.1.1/activation.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/javamail-1.4.1/mail.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/jdepend-2.9/lib/jdepend-2.9.jar:\
${SB_SRC_JZLIB}:${SB_SRC_JSCH}:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/junit4.3.1/junit-4.3.1.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/commons-logging-1.1.1/commons-logging-1.1.1.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/commons-net-1.4.1/commons-net-1.4.1.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/apache-log4j-1.2.15/log4j-1.2.15.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/jakarta-oro-2.0.8/jakarta-oro-2.0.8.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/bsf-2.4.0/lib/bsf.jar:\
${SB_BUILD_PREFIX}/xml-commons-resolver-1.2/resolver.jar" \
./build.sh -Ddist.dir=${SB_INSTALL_PREFIX} dist

# fix path to config file
${SB_PATH_SED} -i -e "\
s!/etc/ant.conf!${_sysconfdir}/ant.conf!;" ${SB_INSTALL_PREFIX}/bin/ant
${SB_PATH_INSTALL} -m 644 -o root -g 0 /dev/null ${_sysconfdir}/ant.conf

${SB_PATH_SED} -i -e "\
s!/usr/bin/perl!${SB_VAR_PERL}/bin/perl!; \
s!/usr/bin/python!${SB_VAR_PYTHON}/bin/python!;" \
${SB_INSTALL_PREFIX}/contrib/*.pl \
${SB_INSTALL_PREFIX}/contrib/*.py
]]>
    </install>

    <licenses>
      <license path="apache-2.0.license"/>

      <license module="jakarta-oro" path="apache-1.1.license"/>

      <license module="antlr">
        <para><command>SOFTWARE RIGHTS</command></para>
        <para skip="0">ANTLR 1989-2004 Developed by Terence Parr</para>
        <para>Partially supported by University of San Francisco &amp;
jGuru.com</para>
        <para>We reserve no legal rights to the ANTLR--it is fully in
the public domain. An individual or company may do whatever they wish
with source code distributed with ANTLR or the code generated by ANTLR,
including the incorporation of ANTLR, or its output, into commerical
software.</para>
        <para>We encourage users to develop software with ANTLR.
However, we do ask that credit is given to us for developing ANTLR. By
"credit", we mean that if you use ANTLR or incorporate any source code
into one of your programs (commercial product, research project, or
otherwise) that you acknowledge this fact somewhere in the
documentation, research report, etc... If you like ANTLR and have
developed a nice tool with the output, please mention that you developed
it using ANTLR. In addition, we ask that the headers remain intact in
our source code. As long as thee guidelines are kept, we expect to
continue enhancing this system and expect to make other tools available
as they are completed.</para>
        <para>The primary ANTLR guy:</para>
        <para skip="0">Terence Parr</para>
        <para skip="0">parrt@cs.usfca.edu</para>
        <para>parrt@antlr.org</para>
      </license>

      <license module="junit">
        <para>Common Public License Version 1.0</para>
        <para><command>THE ACCOMPANYING PROGRAM IS PROVIDED UNDER THE
TERMS OF THIS COMMON PUBLIC LICENSE ("AGREEMENT"). ANY USE, REPRODUCTION
OR DISTRIBUTION OF THE PROGRAM CONSTITUTES RECIPIENT'S ACCEPTANCE OF
THIS AGREEMENT.</command></para>
        <orderedlist>
          <item><para><command>DEFINITIONS</command></para>
          <para>"Contribution" means:</para>
          <orderedlist type="lower-alpha">
            <item><para>in the case of the initial Contributor, the
initial code and documentation distributed under this Agreement,
and</para></item>
            <item><para>in the case of each subsequent
Contributor:</para>
            <orderedlist type="lower-roman">
              <item><para>changes to the Program, and</para></item>
              <item><para>additions to the Program;</para></item>
            </orderedlist></item>
          </orderedlist>
          <para>where such changes and/or additions to the Program
originate from and are distributed by that particular Contributor. A
Contribution 'originates' from a Contributor if it was added to the
Program by such Contributor itself or anyone acting on such
Contributor's behalf. Contributions do not include additions to the
Program which:</para>
          <orderedlist type="lower-roman">
            <item><para>are separate modules of software distributed
in conjunction with the Program under their own license agreement,
and</para></item>
            <item><para>are not derivative works of the
Program.</para></item>
          </orderedlist>
          <para>"Contributor" means any person or entity that
distributes the Program.</para>
          <para>"Licensed Patents " mean patent claims licensable by a
Contributor which are necessarily infringed by the use or sale of its
Contribution alone or when combined with the Program.</para>
          <para>"Program" means the Contributions distributed in
accordance with this Agreement.</para>
          <para>"Recipient" means anyone who receives the Program under
this Agreement, including all Contributors.</para></item>
          <item><para><command>GRANT OF RIGHTS</command></para>
          <orderedlist type="lower-alpha">
            <item><para>Subject to the terms of this Agreement, each
Contributor hereby grants Recipient a non-exclusive, worldwide,
royalty-free copyright license to reproduce, prepare derivative works
of, publicly display, publicly perform, distribute and sublicense the
Contribution of such Contributor, if any, and such derivative works, in
source code and object code form.</para></item>
            <item><para>Subject to the terms of this Agreement, each
Contributor hereby grants Recipient a non-exclusive, worldwide,
royalty-free patent license under Licensed Patents to make, use, sell,
offer to sell, import and otherwise transfer the Contribution of such
Contributor, if any, in source code and object code form. This patent
license shall apply to the combination of the Contribution and the
Program if, at the time the Contribution is added by the Contributor,
such addition of the Contribution causes such combination to be covered
by the Licensed Patents. The patent license shall not apply to any other
combinations which include the Contribution. No hardware per se is
licensed hereunder.</para></item>
            <item><para>Recipient understands that although each
Contributor grants the licenses to its Contributions set forth herein,
no assurances are provided by any Contributor that the Program does not
infringe the patent or other intellectual property rights of any other
entity. Each Contributor disclaims any liability to Recipient for claims
brought by any other entity based on infringement of intellectual
property rights or otherwise. As a condition to exercising the rights
and licenses granted hereunder, each Recipient hereby assumes sole
responsibility to secure any other intellectual property rights needed,
if any. For example, if a third party patent license is required to
allow Recipient to distribute the Program, it is Recipient's
responsibility to acquire that license before distributing the
Program.</para></item>
            <item><para>Each Contributor represents that to its
knowledge it has sufficient copyright rights in its Contribution, if
any, to grant the copyright license set forth in this
Agreement.</para></item>
          </orderedlist></item>
          <item><para><command>REQUIREMENTS</command></para>
          <para>A Contributor may choose to distribute the Program in object code form under its
own license agreement, provided that:</para>
          <orderedlist type="lower-alpha">
            <item><para>it complies with the terms and conditions of
this Agreement; and</para></item>
            <item><para>its license agreement:</para>
            <orderedlist type="lower-roman">
              <item><para>effectively disclaims on behalf of all
Contributors all warranties and conditions, express and implied,
including warranties or conditions of title and non-infringement, and
implied warranties or conditions of merchantability and fitness for a
particular purpose;</para></item>
              <item><para>effectively excludes on behalf of all
Contributors all liability for damages, including direct, indirect,
special, incidental and consequential damages, such as lost
profits;</para></item>
              <item><para>states that any provisions which differ
from this Agreement are offered by that Contributor alone and not by any
other party; and</para></item>
              <item><para>states that source code for the Program is
available from such Contributor, and informs licensees how to obtain it
in a reasonable manner on or through a medium customarily used for
software exchange.</para></item>
            </orderedlist></item>
          </orderedlist>
          <para>When the Program is made available in source code
form:</para>
          <orderedlist type="lower-alpha">
            <item><para>it must be made available under this
Agreement; and</para></item>
            <item><para>copy of this Agreement must be included with
each copy of the Program. </para></item>
          </orderedlist>
          <para>Contributors may not remove or alter any copyright
notices contained within the Program.</para>
          <para>Each Contributor must identify itself as the
originator of its Contribution, if any, in a manner that reasonably
allows subsequent Recipients to identify the originator of the
Contribution.</para></item>
          <item><para><command>COMMERCIAL DISTRIBUTION</command></para>
          <para>Commercial distributors of software may accept certain
responsibilities with respect to end users, business partners and the
like. While this license is intended to facilitate the commercial use of
the Program, the Contributor who includes the Program in a commercial
product offering should do so in a manner which does not create
potential liability for other Contributors. Therefore, if a Contributor
includes the Program in a commercial product offering, such Contributor
("Commercial Contributor") hereby agrees to defend and indemnify every
other Contributor ("Indemnified Contributor") against any losses,
damages and costs (collectively "Losses") arising from claims, lawsuits
and other legal actions brought by a third party against the Indemnified
Contributor to the extent caused by the acts or omissions of such
Commercial Contributor in connection with its distribution of the
Program in a commercial product offering. The obligations in this
section do not apply to any claims or Losses relating to any actual or
alleged intellectual property infringement. In order to qualify, an
Indemnified Contributor must:</para>
          <orderedlist type="lower-alpha">
            <item><para>promptly notify the Commercial Contributor in
writing of such claim, and</para></item>
            <item><para>allow the Commercial Contributor to control,
and cooperate with the Commercial Contributor in, the defense and any
related settlement negotiations.</para></item>
          </orderedlist>
          <para>The Indemnified Contributor may participate in any
such claim at its own expense.</para>
          <para>For example, a Contributor might include the Program
in a commercial product offering, Product X. That Contributor is then a
Commercial Contributor. If that Commercial Contributor then makes
performance claims, or offers warranties related to Product X, those
performance claims and warranties are such Commercial Contributor's
responsibility alone. Under this section, the Commercial Contributor
would have to defend claims against the other Contributors related to
those performance claims and warranties, and if a court requires any
other Contributor to pay any damages as a result, the Commercial
Contributor must pay those damages.</para></item>
          <item><para><command>NO WARRANTY</command></para>
          <para><command>EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY SET FORTH IN THIS
AGREEMENT, THE PROGRAM IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT
WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED
INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, ANY WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF TITLE,
NON-INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
PURPOSE.</command> Each Recipient is solely responsible for determining
the appropriateness of using and distributing the Program and assumes
all risks associated with its exercise of rights under this Agreement,
including but not limited to the risks and costs of program errors,
compliance with applicable laws, damage to or loss of data, programs or
equipment, and unavailability or interruption of operations.</para></item>
          <item><para><command>DISCLAIMER OF LIABILITY</command></para>
          <para><command>EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY SET FORTH IN THIS
AGREEMENT, NEITHER RECIPIENT NOR ANY CONTRIBUTORS SHALL HAVE ANY
LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR
CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION LOST PROFITS),
HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT,
STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN
ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OR DISTRIBUTION OF THE PROGRAM OR THE EXERCISE OF
ANY RIGHTS GRANTED HEREUNDER, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH
DAMAGES.</command></para></item>
          <item><para><command>GENERAL</command></para>
          <para>If any provision of this Agreement is invalid or
unenforceable under applicable law, it shall not affect the validity or
enforceability of the remainder of the terms of this Agreement, and
without further action by the parties hereto, such provision shall be
reformed to the minimum extent necessary to make such provision valid
and enforceable.</para>
          <para>If Recipient institutes patent litigation against a
Contributor with respect to a patent applicable to software (including a
cross-claim or counterclaim in a lawsuit), then any patent licenses
granted by that Contributor to such Recipient under this Agreement shall
terminate as of the date such litigation is filed. In addition, if
Recipient institutes patent litigation against any entity (including a
cross-claim or counterclaim in a lawsuit) alleging that the Program
itself (excluding combinations of the Program with other software or
hardware) infringes such Recipient's patent(s), then such Recipient's
rights granted under Section 2(b) shall terminate as of the date such
litigation is filed.</para>
          <para>All Recipient's rights under this Agreement shall
terminate if it fails to comply with any of the material terms or
conditions of this Agreement and does not cure such failure in a
reasonable period of time after becoming aware of such noncompliance. If
all Recipient's rights under this Agreement terminate, Recipient agrees
to cease use and distribution of the Program as soon as reasonably
practicable. However, Recipient's obligations under this Agreement and
any licenses granted by Recipient relating to the Program shall continue
and survive.</para>
          <para>Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute copies of
this Agreement, but in order to avoid inconsistency the Agreement is
copyrighted and may only be modified in the following manner. The
Agreement Steward reserves the right to publish new versions (including
revisions) of this Agreement from time to time. No one other than the
Agreement Steward has the right to modify this Agreement. IBM is the
initial Agreement Steward. IBM may assign the responsibility to serve as
the Agreement Steward to a suitable separate entity. Each new version of
the Agreement will be given a distinguishing version number. The Program
(including Contributions) may always be distributed subject to the
version of the Agreement under which it was received. In addition, after
a new version of the Agreement is published, Contributor may elect to
distribute the Program (including its Contributions) under the new
version. Except as expressly stated in Sections 2(a) and 2(b) above,
Recipient receives no rights or licenses to the intellectual property of
any Contributor under this Agreement, whether expressly, by implication,
estoppel or otherwise. All rights in the Program not expressly granted
under this Agreement are reserved.</para>
          <para>This Agreement is governed by the laws of the State of
New York and the intellectual property laws of the United States of
America. No party to this Agreement will bring a legal action under this
Agreement more than one year after the cause of action arose. Each party
waives its rights to a jury trial in any resulting litigation.</para></item>
        </orderedlist>
      </license>

      <license module="dom">
        <para>This license came from:<ulink url="http://www.w3.org/Consortium/Legal/copyright-software-19980720">http://www.w3.org/Consortium/Legal/copyright-software-19980720</ulink></para>
        <para skip="0">W3C (R) SOFTWARE NOTICE AND LICENSE</para>
        <para skip="0">Copyright (C) 1994-2001 World Wide Web Consortium,
<ulink url="http://www.w3.org/">World Wide Web Consortium</ulink>,
(<ulink url="http://www.lcs.mit.edu/">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.inria.fr/">Institut National de Recherche en Informatique et en Automatique</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.keio.ac.jp/">Keio University</ulink>). All Rights
Reserved.</para>
        <para><ulink url="http://www.w3.org/Consortium/Legal/">http://www.w3.org/Consortium/Legal/</ulink></para>
        <para>This W3C work (including software, documents, or other
related items) is being provided by the copyright holders under the
following license. By obtaining, using and/or copying this work, you
(the licensee) agree that you have read, understood, and will comply
with the following terms and conditions:</para>
        <para>Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this
software and its documentation, with or without modification, for any
purpose and without fee or royalty is hereby granted, provided that you
include the following on ALL copies of the software and documentation or
portions thereof, including modifications, that you make:</para>
        <para>The full text of this NOTICE in a location viewable to
users of the redistributed or derivative work.</para>
        <para>Any pre-existing intellectual property disclaimers,
notices, or terms and conditions. If none exist, a short notice of the
following form (hypertext is preferred, text is permitted) should be
used within the body of any redistributed or derivative code:</para>
        <screen>
Copyright (C) [$date-of-software] World Wide Web Consortium, (Massachusetts Institute of
Technology, Institut National de
Recherche en Informatique et en Automatique, Keio University). All Rights Reserved.
http://www.w3.org/Consortium/Legal/
        </screen>

        <para>Notice of any changes or modifications to the W3C files,
including the date changes were made. (We recommend you provide URIs to
the location from which the code is derived.)</para>
        <para><command>THIS SOFTWARE AND DOCUMENTATION IS PROVIDED "AS
IS," AND COPYRIGHT HOLDERS MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES,
EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, WARRANTIES OF
MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE OR THAT THE USE OF
THE SOFTWARE OR DOCUMENTATION WILL NOT INFRINGE ANY THIRD PARTY PATENTS,
COPYRIGHTS, TRADEMARKS OR OTHER RIGHTS. COPYRIGHT HOLDERS WILL NOT BE
LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES
ARISING OUT OF ANY USE OF THE SOFTWARE OR
DOCUMENTATION.</command></para>
        <para>The name and trademarks of copyright holders may NOT be
used in advertising or publicity pertaining to the software without
specific, written prior permission. Title to copyright in this software
and any associated documentation will at all times remain with copyright
holders.</para>
        <para>This formulation of W3C's notice and license became active
on August 14 1998 so as to improve compatibility with GPL. This version
ensures that W3C software licensing terms are no more restrictive than
GPL and consequently W3C software may be distributed in GPL packages.
See the older formulation for the policy prior to this date. Please see
our Copyright FAQ for common questions about using materials from our
site, including specific terms and conditions for packages like libwww,
Amaya, and Jigsaw.</para>
        <para>Other questions about this notice can be directed to
site-policy@w3.org.</para>
      </license>
    </licenses>

    <notes>
      <note type="configuration">
        <para>The default configuration file is
"<command>${SB_INSTALL_PREFIX}/etc/ant.conf</command>".</para>
      </note>

      <note type="usage">
        <para>Ant requires JVM version 1.4 or higher.</para>
      </note>
    </notes>

    <changelog>
      <change date="2012 January 31" revision="5"
      author="Gary V. Vaughan" email="gary@thewrittenword.com">
        <item><para>Add license texts.</para></item>
        <item><para>Add support for AIX 7.</para></item>
        <item><para>Remove support for AIX 4.3 and 5.1.</para></item>
        <item><para>Remove support for HPUX 10.20.</para></item>
        <item><para>Remove support for Solaris 2.6 and 7.</para></item>
        <item><para>Update python dependency from 2.5.2 to
2.7.2.</para></item>
      </change>

      <change date="2011 November 28" revision="4"
      author="Albert Chin-A-Young" email="china@thewrittenword.com">
        <item><para>Updated perl dependency from 5.8.8 to
5.12.2</para></item>
      </change>

      <change date="2010 April 3" revision="3"
      author="Albert Chin-A-Young" email="china@thewrittenword.com">
        <item><para>Include jdepend, jsch support</para></item>
      </change>

      <change date="2009 January 8" revision="2"
      author="Albert Chin-A-Young" email="china@thewrittenword.com">
        <item><para>Force <command>ANT_HOME</command> in invocation
script</para></item>
        <item><para>Include javamail support</para></item>
      </change>
    </changelog>
  </program>
</programs>
