<?xml version="1.0"?>
<packages>
  <package name="tcl" version="8.3.5" revision="3">
    <package-manager name="pkgadd">
      <category>Development/Languages</category>
      <title>Tcl Interpreter</title>
      <vendor>Scriptics, Inc.</vendor>

      <description>
Tcl stands for "tool command language" and is pronounced "tickle". Tcl
is actually two things: a language and a library. First, Tcl is a
simple textual language, intended primarily for issuing commands to
interactive programs such as text editors, debuggers, illustrators,
and shells. It has a simple syntax and is also programmable, so Tcl
users can write command procedures to provide more powerful commands
than those in the built-in set.

Second, Tcl is a library package that can be embedded in application
programs. The Tcl library consists of a parser for the Tcl language,
routines to implement the Tcl built-in commands, and procedures that
allow each application to extend Tcl with additional commands specific
to that application. The application program generates Tcl commands
and passes them to the Tcl parser for execution. Commands may be
generated by reading characters from an input source, or by
associating command strings with elements of the application's user
interface, such as menu entries, buttons, or keystrokes. When the Tcl
library receives commands it parses them into component fields and
executes built-in commands directly. For commands implemented by the
application, Tcl calls back to the application to execute the
commands. In many cases commands will invoke recursive invocations of
the Tcl interpreter by passing in additional strings to execute
(procedures, looping commands, and conditional commands all work in
this way).
      </description>

      <install-name>tcl83</install-name>

      <pkgname-base>TWWtcl83</pkgname-base>

      <version>8.3.5</version>
      <revision>1</revision>

      <wrapper name="tclsh8.3" path="pkg/tclsh8.3-wrapper.c"
        checksum="5c4cefd3aa530645e3c77212f6e9895b"
        checksum-type="md5" size="9170"/>

      <subpkg type="runtime">
        <depend pkgname-base="TWWgc332"
          title="GNU Compiler Collection"
          subpkg="libruntime">v&gt;=3.3.2</depend>
      </subpkg>

      <replace pkgname-base="TWWtcl82"
        install-name="tcl82"/>
      <replace pkgname-base="TWWtcl81"
        install-name="tcl81"/>
      <replace pkgname-base="TWWtcl80"
        install-name="tcl80"/>
    </package-manager>

    <changelog>
      <change date="2004 April 14" revision="3"
      author="Albert Chin-A-Young" email="china@thewrittenword.com">
        <item><para>Fix SEGV in wrapper script</para></item>
      </change>

      <change date="2004 March 25" revision="2"
      author="Albert Chin-A-Young" email="china@thewrittenword.com">
        <item><para>Upgrade TclCurl module from 0.10.4 to
0.11.0</para></item>
        <item><para>Upgrade tcllib module from 1.4 to
1.6</para></item>
      </change>

      <change date="2004 January 26" revision="1"
      author="Albert Chin-A-Young" email="china@thewrittenword.com">
        <item><para>Fix runtime path to -ltcl8.3 in tclsh8.3 binary on
HP-UX</para></item>
      </change>
    </changelog>
  </package>
</packages>
